Leo A. Lerner Papers
Leo A. Lerner Papers
1929-1968
Lerner, Leo Alfred, 1907-1965.
37.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American editor, publisher of Lerner Newspapers, also known as the Chicago Northside Newspapers. Correspondence, incoming and outgoing (1931-1965); personal notebooks, speeches (1941-1962), articles, editorials; clippings, tape recordings, and pocket calendars.
149129
Biographical History
Leo Lerner (1907-1965) was an American newspaper editor and publisher. Born in Chicago on September 20, 1907 (the eldest of ten children), he attended the Chicago Public Schools, Crane Technical High School and Northwestern University, finishing there in 1928 with the help of a scholarship. In 1929 he married Deana Duskin, with whom he had three children, Louis, Robert and Rosanne.
In addition to their home on Marine Drive in Chicago, the Lerners owned the Kettle Moraine Farm in North Lake, Wisconsin.
Leo Lerner's career in the newspaper business began while he was still attending Northwestern University, when he was Night Editor of the Daily Northwestern for two years and Drama Editor for a like period. During the period 1924-28, he filled various editorial positions on the Morton Grove News, the Lincoln Belmont Booster and the North Side Sunday Citizen. He then became a co-partner of A. O. Caplan in the management of sixteen papers, which included most of the earlier group and were known as the Myers Newspapers, with a total circulation at that time of 219,000. Other papers were slowly added. By 1949, after more reorganization, Lerner was President and Treasurer of the group ever since known as the Chicago Northside Newspapers. Growth continued, and by 1958 Lerner was President, Editor, and Publisher, controlling the Myers Publishing Co., the Lincoln Belmont Publishing Co., the Times Home Newspapers (J. L. Johnson Publishing Co.) and the Neighbor Press of Chicago. The following is a list of papers published by the various divisions of the Chicago Northside Newspapers:
Booster Newspapers:
The Booster
Lincoln-Belmont Booster
Lake View Booster
Sheridan Center Booster
The Sunday Booster
Times Home Newspapers:
Jefferson Park Times
Mayfair Times
Norwood-Edison Times
Portage Park Times
Higgins-Oriole Times
Logan-Armitage Booster, which split into Logan Avondale Booster, and Armitage Avenue Booster
North West Sunday Times
Albany-North Park Times
Myers Newspapers:
Edgewater Uptown News
Ravenswood-Lincolnite News
North Town News
Rogers Park News
North Side Star
Life of Niles Township (Thursdays only)
Lerner was deeply involved in public service throughout his life and was active in many social and civic organizations in the Chicago area. He was appointed to the Board of Directors of the Chicago Public Library on November 13, 1936, and remained until 1947, serving as Director after 1943 and greatly expanding and improving the service. In 1940-1941 he was President of the Citizens Schools Committee, which was instrumental in combating corruption and raising the educational standards in Chicago. He was a member of the Americans for Democratic Action, a founder of the liberal Independent Voters of Illinois (1943), a director of the Lincoln-Belmont YMCA, and a member of various hospital improvement groups. During World War II he sponsored and aided a number of European refugees to the United States. He was a member of the Cancer Prevention Center of Chicago from 1958 until his death, serving as Chairman of the Board of Directors from 1962.
Lerner also helped found Roosevelt University, and taught a journalism course there. From 1950 to 1960 he served as president of its Board of Trustees. In 1960 he joined the Board of Trustees of the Scandinavian Seminar, a plan providing nine months of study in any Scandinavian country for qualified students. In 1962, Lerner became a member of the Board of the Chicago Better Business Bureau, and in March of that year he was appointed to the Illinois Parole and Pardon Board. In 1964 President Johnson invited him to join the Citizens Advisory Board of the Community Relations Service.
Active in professional organizations, Lerner was a member of the Abraham Lincoln Memorial Commission in 1955, the Illinois Press Association, National Editorial Association, American Political Science Association, and the Institute of General Semantics. Much in demand as a speaker and author, he also wrote a large number of speeches and articles, and four books: Continental Journey, written during his 1947 tour of Europe, The Itch of Opinion (1956), The Italics Are Mine (1960), and The Truth Ripens, finished just before his death. In addition, he was co-author of Lincoln of the Ages (1960).
Lerner was recognized many times for his contributions both to journalism and to the civic and social life of Chicago. He was the only neighborhood newspaperman accredited by the State Department to cover the United Nations Conference at San Francisco in 1945, and the following year he received the Decalogue Society of Lawyers' Annual Award of Merit. 1961 brought him the Chicago Medal of Merit, presented by Mayor Daley. In 1937 he received the first Editorial Award presented by the Illinois Press Association. He also was the recipient of the National Herrick Award in 1951 and the Publisher of the Year Award in 1953.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Leo A. Lerner Papers consist of correspondence, general subject files, manuscripts and other writings, memorabilia, published materials, and tape recordings. Part of the collection is a separate accession which has not been integrated with the main collection; this material is identified by "(1979 addition)."
Main Collection
The main part of the collection consists of general subject files, personal files, manuscripts, published materials, and tape recordings.
General subject files consists of correspondence, brochures, clippings, reports, memoranda and some housekeeping records. The papers relate to such subjects as business, politics, city, county, state, national and international affairs, colleagues, universities and schools, and religious organizations. Especially noteworthy are the files concerning the Abraham Lincoln Memorial, the Cancer Prevention Center of Chicago, the Chicago Board of Education and the Citizens Schools Committee, the Elmer Gertz folder (for its inclusion of news clippings and correspondence on the Chicago censorship case of Henry Miller's Tropic of Cancer), the Illinois Parole Board, Roosevelt University, Stevenson for President, and the United Nations.
Personal files consists of correspondence, a subject file and journals. Correspondence concerns personal affairs and includes related clippings, mementos, etc. The folders are arranged chronologically. The subject file consists of materials relating to books, trips, and tours, awards, photographs, homes, automobiles, letters to his wife and misc. unidentified papers and notes. The letters to his wife were written during his participation in the 1945 United Nations Conference and contain impressions of people and events. Journals consist of undated personal notebooks and pocket calendars for 1944-1964.
Manuscripts contains speeches, articles, editorial material and misc. materials relating to these manuscripts.
Published materials consist of articles by Leo Lerner, articles about Leo Lerner and miscellaneous published materials.
Tape recordings consist of five tapes made for radio broadcasts. One bears the date 1961 and the remaining four are undated.
1979 Additions
The 1979 additions consist of correspondence, memorabilia, printed material, and writings. Correspondence section includes business, congratulatory and personal subheadings which range from 1927 to 1966. Within this period there is a typed letter signed by Adlai Stevenson and photocopied letters signed by Senator Claude Pepper, Mayor Daly, and Franklin Roosevelt. Memorabilia consists of awards, memorial material of Mr. Lerner and several photographs. Printed material covers a large variety of subjects, and includes four of Mr. Lerner's books, a wide range of editorials, some tape recordings, and other miscellaneous written material.
Arrangement of the Collection
Manuscripts are arranged chronologically by year, 1941-1962, with some undated materials located at the end. Published materials are arranged chronologically within each group, undated materials appearing at the end.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; Publishing, printing and book arts; Lerner, Leo Alfred, 1907-1965 -- Archives.; Journalism.; Journalists -- United States.; Newspaper editors -- United States.; Newspaper publishing -- United States.; Newspapers -- Section, columns, etc. -- Editorials.; Publishers and publishing -- United States.; Chicago (Ill.) -- Archival resources.; Chicago (Ill.) -- Politics and government.; Illinois -- Politics and government.; Articles.; Calendars (documents); Correspondence.; Editorials.; Notebooks.; Speeches (documents); Editors.; Journalists.; Publishers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. Leo Lerner, Feb. 17, 1966.
Inventory
- General Subject File
  - A, miscellaneous, 1937-1964; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Abraham Lincoln Memorial Commission
    - 1942-1956, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Published materials, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Abraham Lincoln Book Shop (Box 3)
  - Abrams Department Store (Box 3)
  - Accredited Home Newspapers of America
    - to 1955 (Box 4)
    - 1958-1965, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Adams, James Luther
    - [Miscellaneous] (Box 4)
    - Festschrift (Box 4)
  - Advertising Council (Box 5)
  - American Arbitration Association (Box 5)
  - American Cable and Radio Corp. (Box 5)
  - American Cancer Society (Box 5)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 5)
  - American Express Co. (Box 5)
  - American Legion Posts (Box 5)
  - American Political Science Association (Box 5)
  - American Friends of the Hebrew University (Box 5)
  - American Red Cross (Box 5)
  - Americans for Democratic Action
    - 1955-1957, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - 1958-1963, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Amlie, Tom (Box 6)
  - Anti-defamation League (Box 6)
  - Anti-Semitism in schools (Box 6)
  - Applications for employment (Box 6)
  - Arbitration case (Box 6)
  - Arvey, Jacob M. (Box 6)
  - Art Institute of Chicago (Box 6)
  - Ash, Harry A. (Box 6)
  - Associated Press (Box 6)
  - Atomic Information (Box 6)
  - Audit bureau of circulations (Box 6)
  - Automobile safety (Box 6)
  - Axford, Roger W. (Box 6)
  - B, miscellaneous, 1935-1955; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - B, miscellaneous, 1956-1965; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Balaban and Katz (Box 8)
  - Barton's Candy Co. (Box 8)
  - Bell and Howell (Box 8)
  - Benson Associates (Box 8)
  - Bergman, Joe (Box 8)
  - Bernhard, Edgar (Box 8)
  - Binswanger, Charles A. (Box 8)
  - Blair, Edward McCormick (Box 8)
  - Blaine, Mrs. Emmons (Anita) (Box 8)
  - Blewett (Box 8)
  - B'nai Zion Congregation (Rabbi Henry Fisher) (Box 9)
  - B'nai Berth and Lodges (Box 9)
  - Book Publishers (Box 9)
  - Boyle, Charles (Box 9)
  - Bradley, Preston (Box 9)
  - Braude, J. M. (Box 9)
  - W. Brain Co. (Box 9)
  - Broadcast Music Inc. (Carl Haverlin) (Box 9)
  - Brookstone, Louis (Box 9)
  - Broun Award (Box 9)
  - Broyles Committee (Box 9)
  - Buescher, Walter (Box 9)
  - Burck, Jacob (Box 9)
  - Buik, George C. (Box 10)
  - Burman, Judge Henry L. (Box 10)
  - Bureau on Jewish Employment Problems (Box 10)
  - Burnette, Wells (Box 10)
  - C, miscellaneous, 1943-1952; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - C, miscellaneous, 1953-1964; 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Cancer Prevention Center of Chicago
    - 1952-1957 (Box 11)
    - 1958-1960, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - 1961-1964, 4 folders (Box 13)
    - 1965 (Box 14)
  - Capital Times (Box 14)
  - Caplan, A. O. (Box 14)
  - Carey, Archibald (Box 14)
  - Carpentier, Charles F. (Box 14)
  - Casey, Verne (Box 14)
  - Castle, Latham (Box 14)
  - Catholic Youth Organization (Box 14)
  - Cherdron, Irving T. (Box 14)
  - Cherry, Senator Robert E. (Box 14)
  - Chicago Accredited Newspapers (Box 14)
  - Chicago Allied Printing Trades Council (Box 14)
  - Chicago's American (Box 14)
  - Chicago Association of Commerce and Industry (Box 14)
  - Chicago Bar Association (Box 14)
  - Chicago Bears Football Club (George Halas) (Box 14)
  - Chicago Better Business Bureau (Box 14)
  - Chicago Board of Education (Box 14)
  - Chicago Board of Education (Box 14)
  - Chicago Board of Election Commissioners (Box 14)
  - Chicago Board of Health (Dr. Andelmann) (Box 14)
  - Chicago Commission on Human Relations (Box 14)
  - Chicago Community Music Foundation (Box 15)
  - Chicago Council on Farm Relations (Box 15)
  - Chicago Cubs (Box 15)
  - Chicago Daily News (Box 15)
  - Chicago Daily News (Box 15)
  - Chicago Housing (Box 15)
  - Chicago Housing Authority (Box 15)
  - Chicago Medical School (Box 15)
  - Chicago Memorial Hospital (Box 15)
  - Chicago Motor Club (Box 15)
  - Chicago Northwestern Railway System (Box 15)
  - Chicago Park District, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Chicago Police Department (Box 15)
  - Chicago Police Department, Superintendent of Police, Orlando Wilson (Box 15)
  - Chicago Press Club (Box 15)
  - Chicago Public Library (Box 15)
  - Chicago Rabbinical Association (Box 15)
  - Chicago Safety Council (Box 15)
  - Chicago Stereotypers (Box 15)
  - Chicago Symphony Orchestra (Box 16)
  - Chicago Teachers Union (Box 16)
  - Chicago Transportation (Box 16)
  - Chicago Transit Authority (Box 16)
  - Chicago Tribune (Box 16)
  - Chicago Typographical Union (Box 16)
  - Chicago Web Printing Pressman's Union (Box 16)
  - Chicago White Sox (Box 16)
  - Child Labor Laws (Box 16)
  - Christian Science (Box 16)
  - Christmas advertising letter (Box 16)
  - Christmas list (Box 16)
  - Church, Mrs. Ralph (Box 16)
  - Circulation Dept. (Box 16)
  - Citadel Press (Box 16)
  - Citizens of Greater Chicago (Box 16)
  - Citizens Schools Committee (Box 16)
  - Citizens Traffic Safety Board (Box 16)
  - City Club of Chicago (Box 16)
  - City News Bureau (Box 16)
  - City of Hope (Box 16)
  - Civil Intelligence Service (Box 17)
  - Civil Service Commission (Box 17)
  - Civil Service Centennial Commission (Box 17)
  - Civil War Round Table (Box 17)
  - Civilian defense (Box 17)
  - Classified Department correspondence (Box 17)
  - Clinton, Stanford (Box 17)
  - Cohen, Nathan M. (Box 17)
  - Cole-Finder Records (Box 17)
  - Combined Jewish Appeal (Box 17)
  - Combined Insurance Co. of America (Box 17)
  - Commercial Insurance Co. (Box 17)
  - Commissions (Box 17)
  - Commercial National Bank (Box 17)
  - Community Fund of Chicago (Box 17)
  - Conant, Howard R. (Box 17)
  - Consolidated Balance Sheets (Box 17)
  - Consulates (Box 17)
  - Cook County Office of the Department of Purchase (Box 17)
  - Cook County Democratic Committee (Box 17)
  - Cook County National and Cook Co. Central Democratic Committee (Box 17)
  - Cook Electric (Box 17)
  - Crawford's Department Store (Sam & Al Garber) (Box 17)
  - Credit Department (Box 17)
  - Culberg Asbestos Co. (Box 17)
  - Cunniff, Luke F. (Box 17)
  - Cushman, Elliott L. - San Diego Shopping News (Box 18)
  - D, miscellaneous, 1942-1964; 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Daily cash sales reports, 1955 (Box 18)
  - Daily Compass (Box 18)
  - Daley, Richard J., Mayor, 1954-1965; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Daniels, Jonathan (Box 18)
  - Danon, Richard (Box 19)
  - Davis, Dick - Transcript Publications (Box 19)
  - Day, J. Edward, Postmaster General, Washington, D.C. (Box 19)
  - Deadlines - Myers (Box 19)
  - Decalogue Society of Lawyers, 1946-1965; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Delfino, Adrian (Box 19)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1955 (Box 19)
  - Democratic National Convention (Box 19)
  - Denoyer Geppart Co. (Box 19)
  - Delove, S. L. (Box 19)
  - Department of Commerce (Box 19)
  - Despres, Leon (Box 19)
  - Detroit Shopping News (Box 19)
  - Devon Avenue Parking Project (Box 19)
  - Devon Avenue Paving (Box 19)
  - Devon North Town State Bank, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Dewitt, Edward - Wallace Tubes Com. (Box 19)
  - Diamond Jubilee Edition, 1889-1964 (Box 19)
  - Dipletro, Nick - Chicago Typographers Union (Box 19)
  - Dirksen, Senator E. M. (Box 19)
  - Dollar Day correspondence (Box 20)
  - Donaghue, Pete (Box 20)
  - Doubleday (Box 20)
  - Douglas, Senator Paul H., 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Drury, John (Box 20)
  - Duffy, John J. - President, Cook County Board of Commissioners (Box 20)
  - Dun & Bradstreet (Box 20)
  - E, miscellaneous, 1951-1964; 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Easy Travel (Box 21)
  - Edgewater Folk Fair (Box 21)
  - Editor and Publisher, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Editorial Style (Box 21)
  - Editor's Mail, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Box 21)
  - Elliott, Ivan A. (Box 21)
  - Electric Association (Box 21)
  - Encampment for Citizenship (Box 21)
  - Engraving Costs (Box 21)
  - Equipment-Machinery (Box 21)
  - Equitable Life Assurance Co. (Box 21)
  - Erickson, William N. - Board of Commissioners of Cook Co. (Box 21)
  - Evanston Broadcasting - WNMP (Box 21)
  - Evanston Mail (Box 21)
  - Everston, Joseph (Box 22)
  - Excess profits (Box 22)
  - Executive Committee meetings (Box 22)
  - F, miscellaneous, 1943-1964; 4 folders (Box 22)
  - Fazackerly, Donald (Box 22)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) (Box 22)
  - Charles R. Feldstein and Co. (Box 23)
  - Ferstl, Joseph (Box 23)
  - Finnegan, Edward R. (Box 23)
  - Finnegan Memorial (Box 23)
  - First Commercial Bank of Chicago (Box 23)
  - Fleck & Pollack (Box 23)
  - Four year college (Box 23)
  - Fox, Seymour (Box 23)
  - Frank, Morron (Box 23)
  - Franklin Association (Box 23)
  - Free Press (Box 23)
  - French Provisional Government (Box 23)
  - G, miscellaneous, 1943-1954; 2 folders (Box 23)
  - G, miscellaneous, 1955-1965; 3 folders (Box 24)
  - Gansberg, Joan (Box 24)
  - Gavin, Mrs. Ruth (Box 24)
  - General Semantics, 1934-1964; 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Gerber, Ann (Box 25)
  - Gertz, Elmer (Box 25)
  - Glasser, Charles (Box 25)
  - Glasser, Mrs. Morris (Box 25)
  - Glazer, Barney (Box 25)
  - Gluck-Citron, Inc. (Box 25)
  - Goddess, Norman (Box 25)
  - Goldblatt's Department Store (Box 25)
  - Goldwater, Barry (Box 25)
  - Gordon, Lou (Box 25)
  - Goss Printing Press Co. (Box 25)
  - Grace, Edward (Springfield Shopping News) (Box 25)
  - Green, Dwight (Box 25)
  - Greisdorf, Myron (Box 25)
  - Gunlock, Virgil E. (Box 25)
  - Gutknecht, Judge John J. (Box 25)
  - H, miscellaneous, 1941-1965; 4 folders (Box 26)
  - Headline Club, Sigma Delta Chi (Box 27)
  - Hirsh, Alderman Morris H. (Box 27)
  - Hoe & Co. (Box 27)
  - Hoellen, Alderman John J. (Box 27)
  - Hoffenberg, Sol (Box 27)
  - Holleb, Marshall (Box 27)
  - Holleb, Paul (Box 27)
  - Horwich, Bernard (Jewish Community Center) (Box 27)
  - Hull House (Box 27)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H. (Box 27)
  - Huppert, Jerome (Box 27)
  - I, miscellaneous, 1943-1964 (Box 27)
  - Illinois Bell Telephone Co. (Box 27)
  - Illinois, House Bills (Box 27)
  - Illinois, House Banking Committee (Box 27)
  - Illinois Inst. of Technology (Box 28)
  - Illinois, Legals (Box 28)
  - Illinois Lincoln Sesquicentennial Commission (Box 28)
  - Illinois Parole Board, March, 1962 (Box 28)
    See also Leopold, Nathan.
  - Illinois Parole Board, Apr., 1962-1964 (Box 28)
  - Illinois Press Association (Box 28)
  - Illinois Secretary of State (Box 28)
  - Illinois State Highway Commission (Box 29)
  - Illinois State Historical Library (Box 29)
  - Inaugurations (V.S. Pres.), 1949; 1961 (Box 29)
  - Independent voters of Illinois, 1945-1957; 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Inland Steel (Box 29)
  - Insurance (miscellaneous) (Box 29)
  - Interstate Steel Co. (Box 29)
  - Israel Bonds (Box 29)
  - J, miscellaneous, 1943-1964; 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Jacobs, Sidney J. (Box 30)
  - Janowitz, Morris (Box 30)
  - Hernberg, Pete (Box 30)
  - Jewish Federation (Box 30)
  - Jewish organizations (Box 30)
  - Jingle winners (Box 30)
  - John Birch Society (Box 30)
  - John Price Jones Co. (Box 30)
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines (Box 30)
  - Judges (Box 30)
  - Justin Furniture Co. (Box 30)
  - K, miscellaneous, 1943-1957; 3 folders (Box 30)
  - K, miscellaneous, 1958-1964 (Box 31)
  - Kelly, Edward J., Mayor (Box 31)
  - Kennedy, John F. (Box 31)
  - Kennelly, Martin, Mayor (Box 31)
  - Kerner, Otto, Governor (Box 31)
  - Kinnare, Paul, 1950-1961; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Kinnare, Robert (Box 32)
  - Kiwanis Clubs (Box 32)
  - Klopp, Clarence G. (Box 32)
  - Koinonia Farm (Box 32)
  - Komaiko, Charles (Box 32)
  - Korshak, Marchall (Box 32)
  - Kravtter, Betty Bialk (Box 32)
  - Krawchek, Julian (Box 32)
  - Krug, Mark M. (Box 32)
  - Kukla, Fran and Ollie (Box 32)
  - L, miscellaneous, 1943-1950 (Box 32)
  - L, miscellaneous, 1951-1965; 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Lake Meadows Hospital
    - 1955-1956, 2 folders (Box 33)
    - 1956 (Box 34)
  - Lakeview Citizens' Council (Box 34)
  - Lakeview Trust and Savings (Box 34)
  - Lapp, John (Box 34)
  - League of Women Voters of Chicago (Box 34)
  - Lear, Les (Box 34)
  - Le Blane Corporation (Box 34)
  - Lennon and Rose (Box 34)
  - Leopold, Nathan (Box 34)
  - Lepawsky, Albert (Box 34)
  - Lerner, Dora (Box 34)
  - Lerner, Edward (Box 34)
  - Lerner, Louis (Box 34)
  - Lerner, Robert (Box 34)
  - Levy, Russell (Box 34)
  - Lewis, Fulton, Jr. (Box 35)
  - Libel information (Box 35)
  - Life of Niles Township, 1958-1964; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Lincoln Belmont Booster, 1958; 1962-1964; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Lincoln Belmont Business Association (Box 36)
  - Lincoln Belmont Parking (Box 36)
  - Lincoln Square Savings and Loan Association, 1957-1959; 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Little City (Box 36)
  - Long, Valerie Zawila (Box 36)
  - Lorenz, Francis F. (Box 36)
  - Loukas, James P. (Box 36)
  - Lowenthal, Mrs. Alfred (Box 36)
  - Loyalty oath, 1947-1949 (Box 36)
  - M, miscellaneous, 1943-1957; 5 folders (Box 37)
  - M, miscellaneous, 1958-1965; 2 folders (Box 38)
  - MacArthur editorial - reaction (Box 38)
  - McCallister, Frank (Box 38)
  - McCormick Place (Box 38)
  - McCrohan, Margaret (Box 38)
  - McCulloch, Frank (Box 38)
  - MacDougall, Curtis D. (Box 38)
  - McFetridge, William (Box 38)
  - Maga, Don (Box 39)
  - Magazines & newspapers, miscellaneous (Box 39)
  - Mail promotion (Box 39)
  - Maps (Box 39)
  - Maremont, Arnold (Box 39)
  - Margolis, Richard (Box 39)
  - Marina City (Box 39)
  - Marovitz, Abraham L. (Box 39)
  - Marquis Publications (Box 39)
  - Marshall Field & Co. (Box 39)
  - Mayers, Dr. Benedict (Box 39)
  - Mayo Clinics (Box 39)
  - Mellus, William M. (Box 39)
  - Metropolitan Fair and Exposition Authority (Box 39)
  - Millar, John H. (Box 39)
  - Milwaukee Journal (Box 39)
  - Modern Poetry Association (Box 40)
  - Montmorency Paper Co., 1943-1958; 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Montgomery Ward (Box 40)
  - Moran, Jim (Box 40)
  - Movie script (Box 40)
  - Museum of Science and Industry (Box 40)
  - Myers, Thomas Jr. (Box 40)
  - Myers family (Box 40)
  - Myers Publishing Co. (Box 40)
  - Myers Publishing Co., misc. materials (Box 41)
  - Myers travel bureau (Box 41)
  - N, miscellaneous, 1943-1964; 3 folders (Box 41)
  - Narcotics & Alcoholism (Box 41)
  - Nathanson, Ben (East side shopper) (Box 41)
  - The Nation (Box 41)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews (Box 41)
  - National Editorial Association, 1950-1957; 1961-1965; 2 folders (Box 41)
  - National Education Association (Box 42)
  - National Forum (Box 42)
  - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis (Box 42)
  - National Jewish Hospital (Box 42)
  - National Lawyers Guild (Box 42)
  - Navy League of U.S. (Box 42)
  - New Republic (Harrison, Gil) (Box 42)
  - Newman, Danny (Box 42)
  - Newsprint information (Box 42)
  - Newsprint supplies (Box 42)
  - North Shore National Bank (Box 42)